Finding Aid for the Willard Brownell Jewell Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Willard Brownell Jewell Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0229
16.38 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
Jewell, Wlllard Brownell, born in Little Compton, R.I., April 4, 1899. Graduated from Mount Harmon Sohool for Boys 1918, Seaman U.S. Navy Sept. 1918 - Dec. 1918, Ships Carpenter U.S. Merchant Marine Feb. 1919 - Aug. 1919, PhB Brown Univ. 1923, PhD Princeton Univ. 1926, Asst. Prof. Vanderbilt Univ. 1926-1938, Asso. Prof. Vanderbilt 1938-., Visiting Prof, of Geology, Summer Sohool, Colorado College 1935, Director Vanderbilt Summer Field Trip in Geology, summers of 1929, 1930 and 1936. Asst. U.S. Geol. Survey (Alaskan Branch) 1924-1925, Asso. Geologist (part time) Tenn. Geol. Survey 1927-. Asst. Geologist, Newfoundland Geol. Survey 1937. Member of the Tenn. Acad, of Science and the Soc. of Econ. Geologists. Publications and research on the Coast Range Intrusives of Alaska and British Columbia, Mineral Deposits of the Salmon River Area, Hyder District, Alaska, Geology and Mineral Resources of Hardin County, Tenn., Geology and Mineral Deposits of the Baie d'Espoir Region, Newfoundland and Barite-Fluorite-Sphalerite-Galena Veins of Central Tennessee. Died June 21, 1969
Obituary:
It is with sorrow, regret, and a deep sense of loss that the Faculty of the College of Arts and Science records the passing on June 21, 1969, of WILLARD BROWNELL JEWELL, professor emeritus of geology, after forty two years of most distinguished service to Vanderbltt University.
The Faculty extends Its deepest sympathy to the family of Professor Jewell and hopes that they will find some small measure of comfort in the assurance that the University and his colleagues will long revere his memory and be grateful for his outstanding stature as a scholar, teacher, and administrator as well as for the many other Indispensable and varied services he rendered the University.
Wlllard Brownell Jewell was born on April 4, 1899, In Little Compton, Rhode Island, where he was returned to rest. He attended the public schools there until he entered Mt. Hermon School In the Connecticut Valley of Massachusetts in 1915. He graduated from Mt. Hermon In 1918 and the following autumn enrolled In Brown University. His freshman year was interrupted, but after part of a year as a petty officer In the Merchant Marine he returned to Brown and graduated with honors in 1923. He then went to Princeton University for his graduate work and received his Ph.D. In Geology there in 1926.
While at Princeton, Dr. Jewell married Ann Hennessey of Fall River, Massachusetts. Their children are John William, Barbara Ann Pond, and Richard Brownell.
In September. 1926, Dr. Jewell came to Vanderbilt University as Assistant Professor of Geology. He remained at Vanderbilt rising to Associate Professor in 1937 and to full Professor and Chairman of the Department of Geology In 1942. He early interested himself in university affairs - curriculum, counseling, teaching, and students. He served on many university committees, often as chairman, such as those on the Advisory System, Athletics, Senior College, Veterans, Curriculum, Student Christian Association, Library, Natural Sciences, and Faculty Committee to the Board of Trust. He was elected an original member of both the Faculty Council and the University Senate. He served as Chairman of the Campus Committee tn the $30 Million for Vanderbilt Campaign, and for fifteen years was secretary of the College of Arts and Science Faculty.
Dr. Jewell's professional work ranged from Alaska and Newfoundland to Tennessee and North Carolina. His primary interest was always the study of mineral deposits, both ores and industrial minerals. The results of these studies have been published principally in bulletins of various geological surveys.
He was a member or fellow of several professional societies including The Geological Society of America, and served as chairman of its Southeastern Section, in 1962 he was president of the Tennessee Academy of Science. He was a member of ODK, Sigma Xi, and Phi Beta Kappa. He served as president of the Vanderbilt chapters of Sigma Xi and Phi Beta Kappa. From 1949 to 1951 he was a member of the Tennessee Conservation Commission under Governor Browning.
Professor Jewell was also a great teacher. No matter how busy, he was always glad to drop whatever he was doing and talk to students about their problems, scholastic or otherwise. His advice was sympathetic and objective and consequently, highly respected. (This was similarly true of his relations to younger colleagues.) His lectures and explanations always started with first principles or historical background and on these firm foundations, he built, logically and objectively, the thesis or conclusion that seemed best to fit the facts. This objectivity characterized also his relations with his colleagues and his attitude toward his work. His salty New England speech and humor were trademarks.
Those of us who had the very great fortune to serve as his associates, or were closely connected with him in other capacities, will treasure as long as we live his unfailing friendliness and good humor; his courage and intellectual honesty; his example of sound scholarship and duty to truth and principle. Professor W. B. Jewell was one of Vanderbilt's Great Men.
Signed,
Richard G. Stearns
Herbert Weaver
Charles W. W1lson, Jr.
It is here moved that a copy of this Memorial be Included in the Minutes of this meeting of the Faculty of the College of Arts and Science, and that copies be sent to each member of his family.
- Outgoing Correspondence
  - (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - (Folder 5, Box 2)
  - (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - (Folder 7, Box 2)
  - (Folder 8, Box 2)
  - (Folder 9, Box 2)
  - (Folder 10, Box 2)
  - (Folder 11, Box 2)
  - (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - (Folder 13, Box 2)
  - (Folder 14, Box 2)
  - (Folder 15, Box 2)
  - (Folder 16, Box 2)
  - (Folder 17, Box 2)
  - (Folder 18, Box 2)
  - (Folder 19, Box 2)
  - (Folder 20, Box 2)
  - (Folder 21, Box 2)
  - (Folder 22, Box 2)
  - (Folder 23, Box 2)
  - (Folder 24, Box 2)
  - (Folder 25, Box 2)
  - (Folder 26, Box 2)
  - (Folder 27, Box 2)
  - (Folder 28, Box 2)
  - (Folder 29, Box 2)
  - (Folder 30, Box 2)
  - (Folder 31, Box 2)
  - (Folder 32, Box 2)
  - (Folder 33, Box 2)
  - (Folder 34, Box 2)
  - (Folder 35, Box 2)
  - (Folder 36, Box 2)
  - 1960-02/1960-05 + N.D.'s (Folder 37, Box 2)
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Abrams Instrument Corp. (2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Academy of Natl. Sciences (1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Aero Service Crop. (1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Frank (8), 1942-53 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Allott, U.S. Sen. Gordon (1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The American Assoc. of Petrol. Geologists (2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Comm. for Emigre Scholars, Writers etc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Geographical Soc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Geological Inst. (9) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Amer. Inst, of Geonomy (1) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Amer. Inst, of Mining (4) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Amer. Museum of Natl. History (1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Optical Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Petroleum Inst. (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The American University (1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Betty (1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, H.O. (1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, W.J. (1) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Andrews, T.G. (7) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Andrew Technical Service (4) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anglia, Byron (4) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Appleton-Centmry Co., Inc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Assoc. of Geology Teachers (2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Atlanta Oak Flooring Co. (2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Atlantic Refining Co. (2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (1) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Avery, Hilton (1) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ayer, N.W. and Son (2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Babbitt, Samuel F. (1) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    V.U. Dean of Men
  - Barnes, Leverne F., Jr. (1) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Barr, Thomas C, Jr. (2), 1950 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bate, John T. (3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bausch and Lomb Optical Co. (8) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bean, L.L., Inc. (2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Beatty, Richmond C. (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Beehr, Jardner (1) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Behre, Chas. H. (7) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bell and Howell Co. (2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Benedict, A.B. (5) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    V.U. Treasurer
  - Benedict, A.B. (Mrs.) (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bennett, Kelley E. (1) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bergmann, Theo, Shoe Manuf. (1) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Berlin Glove Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Berryhill, Louise Russell (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bingham, John L. (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Asst. Dean - V.U. Arts and Scs.
  - Bircher, Louis J. (2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Birdsong, Troy L. (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Blevins, Wm. A. (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Blue Goose Hotel (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bold, Harold C. (2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bollinger, Homer (2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bookstore (V.U.) (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Born, Kendall E. (2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Branscomb, Harvie (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Brier Hill Collieries (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Betty (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Lytle (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brown, O.E. (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Brown Univ. Alumni Fund (4), 1943-48 and n.d.'s (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Wes (3) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bryan, E.E. (13), 1931-54 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    V.U. Dept. of Bldgs.
  - Buddington, A.F. (10), 1929-51 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Buehler Ltd. (1) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Buford, James L. (2) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    V.U. Director of Admissions and Univ. Registrar
  - Burchard, E.F. (5) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Geological Survey
  - Caldwell, John T. (3) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Pres. - Univ. of Alabama
  - Cambe Log Library (1) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Camp, David h. (2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Campbell, Robert G. (3), 1955 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Canada Dept. of Mines and Technical Surveys (2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cantey, Harry (1) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Carman, J. Ernest (2) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Dept. of Geology - Ohio St. U
  - Carmichael, Oliver C, Jr. (1) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    V.U. Dev. Foundation
  - Carpenter, George K. (1) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Carter Oil Co. (3) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Central Bus Lines, Inc. (5) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Central Scientific Co. (3) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Chemical Rubber Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chaffin, Nora C. (6) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Dean of Women - V.U.
  - Chang, Sukyoon (1) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chemical and Engineering News (1) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cincinnati, Univ. of (1) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    (Dept. of Geol. and Geogr)
  - Clarke, James W. (4), 1950-57 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clement, B.E. (7) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cole, Roy W. (3) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Coleman, Charles (3) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Colgate University (3) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Colorado State Chamber of Comm. (1) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Colvin, John M., Jr. (3) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Commercial Letter Shop (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conley, James (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cooksey, Lindon T. (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Corbett, M. Everett (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Corley, Edmund B. II (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Council of Southern Univs., Inc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Crawford, Meredith P. (4) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Dean - V.U. Junior College
  - Crowl, Ceorge H. (14) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Crucible Club (1) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cullison, James S. (2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Dept. of aeol. - F.S.U.
  - Cumberland Caverns (1) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - W.H. Curtin and Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cunningham, Oliver (Mrs.) (1) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Curtiss, Eugene (2), 1950 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Darby, William J. (1) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Depts. of Med. and Biochem. (V.U)
  - Davidson, Donald (1) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - D.T. Davis Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Davis, C. Jackson (2) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Davis, John H. (1) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Rhodes Scholarship Committee
  - Dravis, Roy Tasco (1) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Inter-American Schools Service
  - Davis, Roy (2) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Nashville Crotto
  - Denoyer-Geppert Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
  - A.B. Dick Co. (1) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dietrich, H.V. (1) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dortch, Nat (3) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dowdy, N. (1) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Duncan, Blanton C. (3) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - E.P. Dutton and Co., Inc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Eastman, Joseph B. (1) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Eastman Kodak (6) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Educators Visual-Aid Service (2), 1947 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Electrochemical Society, Inc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Emory University (2), 1950 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Films (1) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Erpi Classroom Films (5) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Estwing Manufacturing Co. (3) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Eveland, H.E. (1) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Lamar St. College of Tech. (1954)
  - Eversharp, Inc. (1) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Evinrude Motors (2) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Tailoring Co. (2) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fahlquist, Frank E. (2) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fairchild Camera and Instrum. (1) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Farrar, R. Lynn, Jr. (3) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Farrell, Joanne (1) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Ferguson, Herman W. (4), 1943-55 and n.d.'s (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Field, Richard W. (1) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fields, Emmett B. (1) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Director of Summer Session (V
  - Films of Commerce Co. (2) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fishel, W.P. (1) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fisher, Jno. T. (1) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Paul R. Flanigan Mfg. Co. (4) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Flint, George M. (2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Flint, George M., Jr. (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Flores, Frank (3) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Floyd, B.J. (3) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Foose, Richard M. (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Dept. of Geol. - Franklin and Marshall College
  - Ford, William L. III (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fossill Supply Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Franklin Limestone Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Frazer, Marshall G. (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Frazier, Vincent (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fundaburk, Emma Lila (5) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Galloway, J.J.9 (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Dept. of Geol. - Indiana Univ.
  - Gamma Scientific Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Garden St. Minerals (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gardner, Ballard (3) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gardner, Edwin S. (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Bursar, Treasurer - V.U.
  - GBC Sales and Service (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gem Hunter's Guide (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Electric Supply Corp. (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Science Service (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Geochron Laboratories (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Geographical Press (1) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Geological Publishing Co. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Geological Society of America (17) (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Geophoto Services, Inc. (1) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Geoscience Instrums. Corp. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gerber, Jack (1) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Giddings, Lorrain (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Giles, H.T. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ginn and Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Giri, M.B.S. (1) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Glenn, L.C. (2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gonzalez-Reyna, J. (1) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Graves, C. Edward (7) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Green Industries (1) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gregg, Sarah (1) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grieger's (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gude, Arthur James, III (1) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Guffee, Harry J. (Mrs.) (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gurley, W. and L.E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hager, Lee (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hagerman Geologic Assocs. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Halco Scientific Instrums. (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Haley, Francis L. (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hall, Fitzgerald (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hamilton, Watch Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - C.S. Hammond and Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Co. (3) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hardacre, Paul H. (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hardeman, W.O. (2), n.d.'s (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hardy and Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Harper and Brothers (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hart, Henry G. (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hart, Pembroke (7) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hart, Hussell E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Haun, C.C. (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Haupt, Charlotte (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hayes, Wayland (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hefley, Roberta (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Henderson, Gerald D, (5) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    V.U. Bsn. Manager
  - Hennessey, Eliza (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hinson, Vim. H. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hobbs, Hervil (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hodges, Lilian F. (1) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Office of Direc. of Admissions
  - Frank L. Howard Engineering Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Howell, Ben F. (4) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Howland, Arthur L. (2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Humble Oil and Refining Co. (2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hunt, Anne C. (1) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hutchison, John H. (1) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Illinois, Univ. of (4) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Indep. Petrol. Assoc. of Amer. (2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - International Geol. Congress (2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Intl. Magazine Co. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Jarrell-Ash Co. (3) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Jersey Farms Milk Service (1) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Jewell, John (Mrs.) (1) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Johns, W.D. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Floyd (1) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Joint University Libraries (3) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Jones, Earl (C.E. Jones) (2) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Kelley, Everett E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Kelly, W.A. (5), 1927-52 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Kentucky, Univ. of (3) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Keuffel and Esser Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kewaunee Mfg. Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Keystone View Co. (2) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kirkland, J.H. (1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kraua, Edward H. (1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kruger, Fredrick C. (7) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Dept. of Geol. and Geogr. -U.T. - Knoxville
  - Lagemann, Robert (1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lahee, Frederic H. (7) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Amer. Assoc. of Petrol. Geols.
  - Lambert, Dale (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Karl Lambrecht - Optics (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Landes, K.K. (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Dept. of Geol. - Univ. of Mieh
  - Lapiadary Equipment Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Laurence, Robert A. (3) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Lamb, Medora (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ledbetter, Marshall P. (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Lehigh University (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - E. Leitz, Inc. (2) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Lester, J.G. (3) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Dept. of Geol. - Emory Univ.
  - Lewis, Fred J. (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lewis, T.M.N. (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Dept. of Anthrop. - U.T. Knoxville, Tn.
  - Liberty Mutual (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lindenmeyer, Stratton (4) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Litkenhous, E.E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Long, Raymond F. (2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Longmans, Green and Co. (2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Louisiana State Univ (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Love, Fred V. (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lowman, Shepard W. (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lumpkins, Caroline (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Lustro Co. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lyne, Roberta Dillon (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - MacClintock, Paul (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Dept. of Geol. - Princeton Univ
  - Mackay, Donald K. (2) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mahon, Pat (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Maher, Stuart W. (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mailloux, Auguste (2) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Universite Laval
  - Marshall and Bruce Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Marshall, Byron C. (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Martin, Clara J. (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Martin College (2) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Martin, H.R. (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mason, Bill (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mather, Bryant (1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - McCampbell, John C. (4) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - McCary, Charles (1) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - McFarlan, Arthur C. (2) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Dept. of Geol. - Univ. of Ky.
  - McGaw, Robert A. (1) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    News Release Office - V.U.
  - McGraw Hill Book Co. (8) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - McLeod, D.S. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mcquiddy Printing Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Meachan, Reid P. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Bureau of Mineral and Topogr. Survey - Univ. of Ky.
  - Michigan, Univ. of (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miles, A.E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Miller, David G. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mineral Supply House (5), 1941-42 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minaich, Dorothy L. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Asst. to Dean of Women
  - Miser, Hugh D.9 (2) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mississippi, Univ. of (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mistier, A.J. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    U.S. Engineer Office - Charlei ton, S.c.
  - Mitchell, Raoul C. (1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Molecular Models (3) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Moneymaker, Berlen C. (1) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Moore, E.G. (9), 1941-43 and n.d.'s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Morrel, John Smylie (Mrs.) (2) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Mount Hermon Alumni Office (2) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Muncie Gear Works, Inc. (2) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - National Research Council (1) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Natl. Resources Planning Bd, (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Natl. Science Foundation (2), 1954 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Natl. Speleological Society (5) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Natl. Travel Club (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nelson, Vincent E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nesmith, James N. (1) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    V.U. Student Christian Assoc.
  - Newfoundland Dept. of Mines and Resources (2) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Newsweek (1) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - The New York Academy of Sciences (1) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nichols, G.D. (1) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Univ. of Ark.
  - Nichols, Ralph (1) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nicholson, Jake (2) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nilan, George (2) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Northwestern Univ. (3) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - A.J. Nystrom and Co. (1) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Oakley, Paul (1) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Oak Ridge Inst, of Nuclear Studies (1) (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - Oden, Chas R. (1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Oden, Tom E. (1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Office of Naval Research (1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Ogden, David A. (1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Oldsmobile (3) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Olson, C. Daswell (1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Outdoor Life (2) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Ozark Biological Laboratories (11) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Paschal, F.C. (11) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pearson, D.E. (1) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Peebles, Wm. R. (1) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    -
  - The Pennsylvania St. Univ. (1) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Peoples, Joe Webb (12), 1931-58 and n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Perry, Stuart H. (1), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Persson, Lars E. (3) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Phelps, Grace (2) (Box 5, Folder 2)